Sara Kladky

Brooklyn, NY | 717.283.7152 | sara@kladky.tech github.com/Kladky | linkedin.com/in/sara-kladky/

Relevant Skills

Proficient in: JavaScript, Node, Express, React, Sequelize, Git/Github, HTML, CSS, Google Analytics

Knowledgeable: Firebase, Wordpress, JQuery, Sass

Some experience: User testing and research, SQL, Jasmine, PHP, Photoshop, Illustrator

Projects

<u>Align</u> — A web app for setting, tracking, and visualizing long term goals. Responsible for Firebase integration, front-end routes, and React components for goal editing.

Technologies used: Node.js, React, Firebase, D3, Material UI

<u>Scopes</u> — A horoscope generator using Markov chains and source text from the Twitter API. Solo developer on hackathon-style project.

Technologies used: Node.js, Express, React, Twitter API, RiTa.js

<u>Grace Shopper</u> — a simple ecommerce site. Built models, back and front end routes, and React components for creating and editing products. Served as team project manager. *Technologies used:* Node.js, Express, React, Redux, OAuth, Sequelize, Bootstrap

Job History

TED — New York NY

Technical Project Manager *December* 2016 — *April* 2017

- Led product development, analytics, and technical project management for TED-Ed team.
- Grew user base for ed.ted.com from 605K to 1.3MM.
- Redesigned application site for TED-Ed Clubs resulting in a 30% increase in conversions.

Technical Project Management Specialist December 2015 — December 2016

- Designed and implemented user testing strategy for 3 major projects.
- Created Chrome extension in company hackathon which was installed by 827 users.

TED-Ed Web Specialist *December* 2014 — *December* 2015

- Designed and developed custom playlist pages that received over 100k views.
- Built and maintained 5 custom Wordpress blogs for various internal and external TED audiences.

TED-Ed Web Coordinator October 2013—December 2014

 Overhauled customer support workflow by implementing a Desk.com customer support portal and knowledge base.

Clients: Michael Mandiberg, National Resource Center on Domestic Violence, TED — New York NY Freelance Software Developer January 2012 — October 2013

- Oversaw quality assurance and customer support for TED's education initiative.
- Worked with Michael Mandiberg on several code-as-art projects.
- Built two sites for the National Resource Center on Domestic Violence using WordPress.

Education

Grace Hopper Program at Fullstack Academy March 2017 — July 2017

Software development immersive

Bennington College September 2008 — June 2012

Bachelor of Arts

Concentrations: Visual Art and Computer Programming